<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-22T21:23:12+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">(Re)discovering coding</title><subtitle>Programming blog of Hannupekka Sormunen.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New beginnings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/programming/2018/10/22/New-beginnings.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New beginnings" /><published>2018-10-22T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-10-22T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/programming/2018/10/22/New%20beginnings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/programming/2018/10/22/New-beginnings.html">&lt;p&gt;As stated in my &lt;a href=&quot;/programming/2018/10/19/My-first-post.html&quot;&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; blog post I have most experience in software development using C++ -programming language, meaning I still possess some kind of basic understanding of language in question. Because of that I decided that should start my journey from the basics of C++ as a refresher. In my opinion, it is never waste of time to start from the beginning, just to make sure that there is nothing that one have forgotten. I think it will later reduce my frustration when I face some obstacle that I could have overcome easily, if I had refreshed my memory about the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily finding courses that provide one with absolute basics of programming are available far and wide online. For example a simple “best courses to learn C++” Internet-search provides a lot of good pointers where to begin. My first results where &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitaldefynd.com/best-c-plus-plus-tutorial-course-certification/&quot;&gt;Digitaldefynd&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.java67.com/2018/02/5-free-cpp-courses-to-learn-programming.html&quot;&gt;Java67&lt;/a&gt;.
which both provide nice and simple list that provide nice overview of the courses featured. Digitaldefynd ones were mostly about paid courses at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/&quot;&gt;Udemy&lt;/a&gt; online learning portal. Java67 also provided Udemy-course that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/free-learn-c-tutorial-beginners/learn/v4/content&quot;&gt;caught my eye&lt;/a&gt; with the line: “can be completed with any C++ IDE and compiler“ as mentioned previously I’m running virtual machine with Arch Linux on it. so there no need to setup any new software and I’m able to jump right in to the course. For future I also found out about Microsoft edX-courses &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/introduction-c-plus-plus-1?source=aw&amp;amp;awc=6798_1540143660_f3142dbcdbb9302121655eafcec940d3&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/intermediate-c-plus-plus-1?source=aw&amp;amp;awc=6798_1540143661_799ecc6f62e0efa70030b0e80cfb8664&quot;&gt;Intermediate&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/advanced-c-plus-plus-1?source=aw&amp;amp;awc=6798_1540143661_0667aed070e84398f6a426513fc755c2&quot;&gt;Advanced&lt;/a&gt;, which I will check out later, when I want to learn about &lt;a href=&quot;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/&quot;&gt;Microsoft Visual Studio&lt;/a&gt; IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started C++ Tutorial for Complete Beginners and straight away the course lecturer informs that C++ is perfect for AI-applications, which is one of the reasons why I decided that it is my time to start learning programming again. I got my inspiration from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elementsofai.com/fi&quot;&gt;Elements of AI&lt;/a&gt; online course which I completed this September. I was happy to notice, that after of couple of introductory lectures I was already writing lines of code like I used to all those years ago. It felt really nice to start making my own programs along with instructions from lecturer. At one point I even went and checked out my old material from around seven years ago. That is, because during the course I had a flashback about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Makefile&quot;&gt;Makefiles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mst.edu/~cpp/common/hungarian.html&quot;&gt;Hungarian Notation&lt;/a&gt;, so that I could include these at the very beginning and add something from the past to current learning process. I have also learned something new like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cplusplus.com/reference/climits/&quot;&gt;limits.h or climits&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cplusplus.com/reference/ostream/ostream/flush/&quot;&gt;flush&lt;/a&gt; that were previously not taught to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after all that my current plan is that I go through the C++ Tutorial for Complete Beginners daily and then before bedtime I will rehearse what I have just learned with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sololearn.com/&quot;&gt;Sololearn&lt;/a&gt; mobile app that I found for my Android phone that doesn’t need a own compiler installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the lecturer said, when finishing his courses: Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-sorhanp&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My first post!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/programming/2018/10/19/My-first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My first post!" /><published>2018-10-19T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-10-19T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/programming/2018/10/19/My%20first%20post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/programming/2018/10/19/My-first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;17th of October marks the day when my employment contract in a contact center ended and I started a new, or rather continued, my career path towards mastering the art of programming. For the last six and a half year I have worked my way up in a company, that doesn’t have anything to do with software development. Still, I managed to gain experience in leadership, teamwork and ability to work with different kind of people. Most importantly working as a team supervisor at a contact center made me realize that I should keep developing my previously acquired skills in computer science so that I can keep pursuing my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;/about/&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;-page I describe that this blog is my learning diary in my journey to gaining something completely new for my life. I have made preparations to start my learning. I’m currently running Windows operating system and all my past experience in programming has been on C++ programming language using Linux operating system. So I decided that instead of installing  another operating system to my computer or installing necessary programs to Windows (Bash shell etc.). I chose &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/virtualbox.png&quot; alt=&quot;VirtualBox&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found virtualization the best way to begin, because I can test different distros easily and found the one that is best suited for my needs, and likewise do the same with programming tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my first Linux distro I selected &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archlinux.org/&quot;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt; with Plasma desktop environment by KDE:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/arch.png&quot; alt=&quot;Arch Linux&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After couple of weeks of testing I’m currently very happy with this environment and have decided to go ahead and start developing my skills with this configuration. I will report if I have made any changes to my configuration. I will dedicate my next post telling about what kind of materials I have been checking out and which programming courses I will attend next. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-sorhanp&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>